- This meeting is being recorded.
- Okay. I'm going to share my screen.
- How are you, Tammy?
- My lovely. How are you?
- I'm fine. Thank you.
- Good. - I'm going to go on tomorrow night and Saturday.
See how it goes.
- Hopefully this will give you a boost to get on.
- You do amazing.
- All right, ladies.
So welcome to our Body Confidence on webcam, Paul.
It's lovely to see you and see lots of faces on the call as well.
This is something that's come up a lot with what our mentors
have been saying with the girls, but we've heard people as well,
talking a lot about feeling a bit self-conscious on cam
and worrying about your body.
And so we thought it would be a good one to just
for us to get together and chat about it
and share our experiences and just look into a bit more
about why we feel this way and how we can begin to overcome it.
Because I'm sure every single one of us will have had issues
with our body because it's so common, isn't it?
We're all feeling these things.
OK, so let's get stuck in.
If you want to add something at any point
or ask a question or whatever, just feel free to chip in,
put your hand up or just chip in if you want to.
Let's get started.
So what are we aiming for when we're
thinking about body confidence and hopefully overcoming
any issues that we have with our own bodies?
What are we aiming for?
So we're aiming for, hopefully, to be
able to accept and honour our bodies
and their fluctuating states.
So obviously, as women, our bodies
change throughout the month.
And body confidence is about being
able to accept that.
To accept that our bodies don't always look the same.
And just still feeling respect and love and honoring ourselves,
regardless of that.
We're aiming to not to let poor body image hold us back,
because I know that it does, doesn't it?
It holds us back from doing things, from participating
things, from wearing things.
We're aiming to share our vulnerabilities here,
hopefully, and uplift each other,
to embrace our unique appearance and our sensuality, which
we all have, to feel at home in our bodies,
hopefully, because when you're hating on your body,
it's really hard to feel at home in your body, isn't it?
To recognise that the way we see ourselves
might not be how other people see us.
So I probably have a unique, privileged look
into this as a therapist working with--
I've worked with so many, so many people,
and a lot of people with body issues.
And I can assure you that the lens
that you're looking through the world
is heavily influenced by the messages
that you've been given when you're growing up
and by people around you and whatever else,
the way you see yourself might not
be the way other people see you.
And that's even really shockingly so for some people.
So it's really good to talk about some of the stuff
we're going to talk about in this call,
and to think about how you're viewing yourself.
And hopefully, we're aiming to understand
other people's judgments are a reflection of them, and not you.
So are there a reflection of their pain or their misunderstanding?
And if somebody's judging you in a negative way,
it's not about you, it's about them.
So what are some of the reasons that we have poor body image?
So there's loads, isn't there?
There's loads.
But I think it's good to just acknowledge some of these,
and acknowledge that we're all facing all of these things
as women, particularly.
So generational messages.
So if you were a kid and you saw your mum
looking in the mirror and looking at herself
and critiquing her body, or she's on the latest diet,
or these messages that we get from our parents
or whoever's around us, they get passed down
through generations, don't they?
So that's one way that our body image is affected.
Our conditions of worth.
So we grow up thinking that we're a more worthy person
if we look a certain way.
And that is sort of drummed into us
through society, social media, magazines, whatever.
So it really makes us feel and think
and believe different things about ourselves.
It's really at the core of who we think we are, our parents.
Misinformation on health can influence our body image.
Skinny does not mean healthy.
But unfortunately, we've been led to believe
that that is the truth.
And patriarchal systems and capitalism.
So I mean, we need Jess here for this conversation, don't we?
But it's, you know, these are huge systems
under which we live, you know, the fact
that the world is catered to men.
And they're also, you know, largely men in boardrooms
are coming up with things that they want to sell to us
and trying to make us feel bad about our body
so that we buy these products.
So we have to understand, you know,
and sort of acknowledge that there's all--
there's this system that we're living under
and, you know, it's oppressing us.
It's not good for us.
So we have to know when we're being sold to,
you know, when we're being manipulated.
Body trends, you know, I was listening to a podcast,
can't remember what the podcast was now,
but I really liked how they were talking about body image
because they were saying about, you know,
we think that there's this one version
of what a healthy, sexy body is.
But if you look at the body type trends
over, you know, centuries or generations,
they change so much, don't they?
You know, we had the Marilyn Monroe, you know,
way back, you know, the bigger you are,
the wealthier you were and the more desirable you were.
Like body image is something that is a trend.
You know, it changes over time.
And so we can't, you know, all of us individually
be with every trend because it's just not possible
is it for our bodies to merge
with whatever the trends are doing at the time.
So it takes some pressure off to think that, you know,
it's fashion, it's trends.
And we can't always, we can't live like that
to try and live up to that expectation.
Other people's self-hatred, other people's body issues
and other people's trauma, of course,
they impact us as well.
And fake images, I mean, that's a huge one, isn't it?
Fake images on social media, you know,
often we're measuring ourselves
against things which are not even real.
And so, you know, when you see, you know,
the people that you most admire on Instagram or whatever,
just remembering that, you know,
80, 90% of those images are not real.
They've been edited.
So we can't measure, you know, our day-to-day, you know,
appearance of our bodies against somebody's best picture
that's then been edited.
So to reiterate, to reiterate, and then hopefully,
you know, maybe a couple of people might have something
they want to say, you are not the problem.
So starting self-acceptance practices
is about more than just body confidence.
We're talking about body confidence here,
but it's a much bigger thing than that.
It's taking your life back.
So if you're not a slave to an impossible standard,
you can begin to feel less powerless
and you are no longer under the spell of patriarchy.
The problem is not about you, it's not in you,
it's outside of you, it's society.
So when we share our stories,
we begin to feel less alone
and we can externalize some of this stuff
and realise that we're all dealing
with a lot of the same issues.
The people who you see on social media, you think look perfect.
You know, they are feeling self-conscious too.
This, you know, was a surprise to me
when, you know, I first sort of made,
you know, forged a friendship with Georgia.
Georgia, you know, in my eyes, absolutely perfect,
like beautiful, like just stunning body,
like absolutely gorgeous girl.
And, you know, it was a surprise to me
that she'd be really self-conscious,
that she'd be really conscious about her body sometimes
and, you know, really talking to me
and really upset about it.
And so, you know, we never know
what other people are thinking doing.
We're always thinking about our own flaws
and not the fact that other people
are struggling with their body image as well.
So on that note, does anybody have any body image stories
or, you know, does anyone want to share, like,
how they feel or journey that they've been on
with their own body?
You know, anything that, you know,
could help other people to feel less alone.
Yeah, is there, would anybody like to share anything?
- Hi, I'll share, I'll share.
- I can't put my video on
'cause I'm currently watching my funny
'cause I'm just a massive sloth, so.
- Great.
(laughing)
- I think, I just, I think that beauty
is in the eye of the beholder and, like, no matter
what we look like, what size we are, what shape we are,
what we look like.
- There's always someone that's going to think
that that's a really sex age, you know what I mean?
Like, people have different views, don't they,
on everything, like, and how,
like, everyone likes something different.
So I think no matter how much we think,
oh, I don't look like this, I don't look like that,
and I'm so guilty of it.
I'm always moving my face out in pictures
and stuff like that, but there's so many people out there,
like, that have different tastes,
and it wasn't 'til I started coming, really,
like, I always hated my nose,
like, I always wanted, like, a nose job,
and then when I started coming,
I actually realised that guys really liked my nose,
and I did quite well from having, like,
a weird, chank, bigger nose.
So now I'm like, I love it, like, I want to keep it,
'cause it's something a bit different.
Yeah, so I think, just to realise in that,
no matter, like, sort of what you look like
and how you see yourself,
that's not how someone else will see you,
and it doesn't matter anywhere, that's so good to you.
You've got to start loving,
you've got to start loving ourselves, haven't we?
- Yeah.
- Don't realise if we're not validated
by someone else's opinion.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, thank you for sharing, Sammy.
And it's so nice to know how webcam can, like,
make you feel so much better about your body
and about yourself, if you just allow it to,
if you just, like, let down your defences
and allow it to, you meet so many people
that are complimenting you on parts of you
that you didn't like before or that you felt so confident about.
- And it's a massive confidence boost, isn't it?
Like, massively.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, it's lovely.
- It's nice.
- Thank you, Sammy.
- Hi.
- Christi, hello.
- Oh, sorry.
- Thank you, baby.
- Hello.
(laughing)
So I thought I'd share something.
- Yeah.
- So when I was about, like,
I'd say when I first started, like, having sex,
so from public, it sounds a bit young, but, like, 15.
- Up to, like, I'd say about 22.
I used to have this weird, like, obsession with, like,
so I'd never take my clothes,
like, my top half of my clothes when having sex.
So I'd, like, keep my top on because I thought,
like, my boobs were, like, too small and, like,
I don't know, like, boys would say stuff about my body.
So I just had this really bad,
this more fear about, about my boobs and stuff.
But then, when I met, like,
when I met someone who really liked my body,
like, it started to give me more confidence.
And, yeah, I just thought, I thought I'd share that.
Because sometimes it's all about being with the right person
as well, who respects your body.
I obviously chose the wrong men.
- Yeah, I'd say that.
- Yeah, thank you so much for sharing that.
And that's another example of how somebody can be feeling
self-conscious about something, like, wow, looking at you.
And I'm pretty sure I've seen your boobs on a few occasions.
Like, you're so beautiful, you're so stunning.
So just to think about you'd be thinking that way,
it's crazy to me, but we all have insecurities
of some kind at some time, don't we?
- Yeah, so, but now, yeah, I feel a lot more confident.
I think comes done that as well for me.
Obviously, when you speak to these people,
they see different, they see,
when I feel like when men are a lot more mature,
they see women in a different light.
They see them more as beauty rather than,
I'm trying to think of the word.
I'm not very good at explaining things, but yeah,
I think the more mature men get,
the more respect they have as well.
So that's also good for what the confidence.
- Yeah, thank you.
Thank you for sharing that.
- Nice.
- And that makes me think about conversations
we've had Georgia, like, about,
'cause I know we've both been on journeys the past few years,
like, you know, attempting to love our bodies,
which I think we do now.
We've got to that point after a long time of, like,
a lot, probably hundreds of, like, you know,
conversations reassuring, one of us reassuring,
the other one, like, time and time and time again.
But I think a big part of that was about
having the right person as well, wasn't it?
Like, finding these men that were celebrating us so much,
like, even the parts that we are most, like, conscious about,
they were loving it.
So that's definitely, yeah,
that's something I hadn't thought of.
- Yeah, yeah, definitely.
I am, I've also been in similar situations to you, Evie.
Like, with past partners, like,
just not feeling good about myself
because of how they treated me
and how they felt about themselves
was getting reflected on me, you know?
'Cause, like, as Elle said before, it's never about us.
It's always about them if someone's, you know,
being not being nice.
So, yeah, so it's nice to be around someone
who actually adores my body
and makes me realise why I should adore it, too.
But then it makes me think,
no, I'll never want, like, I should never go back
and I should never, like, let myself go back
to that negative thoughts,
even if I am around someone who says, you know,
negative things about me.
And although it's hard, too,
'cause sometimes we say those things about ourselves,
which we shouldn't, it's good to remind ourselves
to, like, come back to love,
come back to just loving our bodies
because, aside from how they look,
they do so much for us, you know?
Like, we're like, oh, I've got this little bit
of extra fat here and this little bit there
and it's like, but our bodies keepin' us going.
It's like, you know, we're breathing.
We're not even thinking about it.
We're able to walk, you know?
If we're lucky enough to be able to do all these things,
so it's more than just the appearance, you know?
We need to, like, thank our bodies for just being able
and strong, like, looking after us, you know?
Looking after all our organs.
- Yeah, and the stuff we put them through,
like, oh my God, I've put my body through, like,
I've put it for years and years of, like, starvation
or, like, stupid diets or, like, whatever, like,
so much stuff would be to our bodies, don't we?
And then we don't even feel grateful for them.
- And, Kirsty, did you wanna say something?
Did you like dieting? - I didn't.
(laughing)
- So, I'm obviously on the plus size.
I know you can't see me.
I'm having a bad day, so I've not put him on.
So, I'm obviously plus sized
and I have always been plus sized.
Like, even being eight years old, I was overweight.
And growing up, I was bullied, I hated myself,
I hated the way I load, because I didn't
look like many of the people.
And I was sort of taught, because everyone else hated me,
it was, I should hate myself.
And I put myself for weight loss surgery
and everything like that.
And, I mean, I lost eight stone,
but then again, most of it back.
And, through putting myself through that,
putting my body through so much,
just to look like the people.
I did learn to love myself through that.
And then, gaining it, yes,
I know I've got health problems and stuff now.
So, I know I need to lose some weight,
but I love my body so much now,
compared to how are you still of it?
And no one can tell me now that, oh, you look terrible.
Yeah, I might do to your eyes,
but you know what, to me, this is who I am.
And I love my body, everything it's been through,
everything I've been through.
My body's took me through that.
And why wouldn't you love yourself for that?
So, that's what I have to say about loving yourself.
Thank you, Kasey.
That actually makes me emotional.
It's so nice to hear someone say that, isn't it?
Like, it's so different to hear someone say that.
Like, I make a point of saying that to other people,
especially women that I feel are so conscious.
I make a point of saying that I love my body, which, you know.
You have to, because some people don't have anyone
to love their body.
Obviously, I am in a relationship
and the others love my body.
But I have to love it before I could let him love it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And it's such a huge thing.
I mean, it's like our, everything, all of us is inside.
This body, isn't it?
Like, it's such a huge thing not to like, you know, yourself.
It definitely is.
Oh, thank you so much for sharing.
Thank you, Kasey.
Does anybody else want to share a bit about
their body image?
No pressure.
No.
No, you're good.
Okay.
I will in a minute, Rala,
I've just got to get this chili con con,
you have to make your wings.
(laughing)
It's cloudy.
Wait, there's one step, let me just tell them.
I love that.
I'm just on the Zoom where you're just going
to get that chili off today, Mike, please.
You'll be fine.
Sorry.
(laughing)
You can't hear anyone by the way,
I've had to know how to meet Ea.
(laughing)
He's him.
Yeah.
(laughing)
Sorry, most of that.
And I just wanted to say, like,
obviously we've opened our little jannies
wherever it's been with men or putting us down
and just things in life happening.
I'm like your mind's body and soul's been through so much.
And I think it has took me a while to realise
that it's more than what you look like.
It's your soul, do you know what I mean?
We're just kind of,
our bodies are just housing this soul to me.
And I've learned to love me as a person.
Like, I've been through so much
and I've learned a lot.
And I'm still learning every day,
but I just feel
and that of Surinha's, myself, I like you.
And I've got a brilliant partner
and I've got a lovely little boy
and he's all of me.
Like, not as all, like, he's love me.
Like, I'm amazing, but--
You are.
He's big me up and you's an only biggest cheerleader.
And so I was me partner.
You know, he's seen me ship myself
when I was giving birth to Joshua
and he still cheers me on and he thinks I'm amazing.
No matter what form I'm in.
And I think we're more than just what we look like.
Do you know what I mean?
And I don't know if you get what I'm trying to say,
but yeah, I've just learned to love me
like this little soul that I've got,
floating around,
rather than I'm a skinny or, you know.
Does that make sense?
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, and it's so nice to be here.
It's so nice to be here.
Yeah, like, I, like, I genuinely love me.
And so, like, I'll sit there
and make myself laugh and just think.
Whoo.
[LAUGHS]
Well, you know, when I was 17,
I was, like, smashing the gym
and I felt confident because I love goods,
but now I feel confident because I'm me.
And I can definitely help with that, you know,
like, when I haven't felt like in the great,
in the best shape of my life,
like, I've still felt confident.
If you get what I mean, sorry,
I'm still supposed to breath from running around the house.
[LAUGHS]
So, yeah.
Yeah.
That's a really good point as well.
Like, there's the type of confidence
where, like, I'm looking off that the past few years,
I've been, I've been so into fitness, like,
so I felt like I've got to, like, my peak fitness
and I've been like, oh, I feel great.
After years, I've been, like, you know,
slightly overweight and not feeling great about myself.
I was like, but then I want to get to that all the time.
I was trying to get to that all the time,
thinking that that was the best type of confidence,
that that was the best feeling.
But then, when you let go of it,
and when you actually, like, you know,
put yourself out there and, like, just embrace yourself
when you're not, when you wouldn't normally,
that's the best type of confidence, isn't it?
Like, you know, like, walk into a sex party
when I'm feeling bloated and my belly's out and I'm curvy
and I'm just like, yeah, fucking love my body.
Like, that's the best type of confidence.
Yeah, it's like the show, so shoot last week, like,
in my mind, I was going to smash the gym and be ripped
and whatever.
And I wasn't, but at the same time, I still felt sexy
and I was, like, surprised by lovely people
who made me feel great, you know what I mean?
And if that was me, like, when I was 17,
I wouldn't have turned up to the show,
so shoot basically, but I did, and it felt great.
Yeah, and you loved me, too.
Yeah, thank you.
Yeah, yeah, oh, thank you, thank you.
Laura, it's so nice to be here.
Thank you for that.
Sorry for the cake, stars.
I hope this Kelly was rescued.
Yeah, it was, it was fine, it was done.
You just have to take it out.
Thank you, Laura.
OK.
Anybody else?
I'm sorry, thank you for anybody else.
So, Maria's here.
Hi, well, if you're near me.
I don't know what to wear, because we may be there.
Hi, Chloe, how are you?
Can you hear me yet?
Sorry if the baby's in the background.
He's still awake, so he's not well.
But he's in command.
And, well, it's about the baby, actually.
So, when I first got pregnant, I was there, tiny deputies.
I mean, I am now to be fair, but, like, I can't even massive.
And I got water ways everywhere, like, if they should as well.
So, yeah, and I was quite big.
And everyone was like, "Oh, you'll snap back, actually."
So, like, you ain't even look like you've ever had a baby.
Like, you're being your own client,
so we should have to get some better.
Some people were constantly saying,
"You'll snap back, you'll do this."
You were that skinny before, you'll be that skinny again,
a week after, a week after.
And then, when the week after came,
and then the second week after,
and then the month, and then the second month,
and then it still wasn't back in my,
well, what I thought was like, "Perfect."
I was like, "Oh, my God, what's wrong with me?"
Like, "Why can't I snap back?"
Like, "Why is everyone else looking dead skinny?"
And then, you started out in the baby.
Like, my boobs are starting to sag,
and they've still got milk in them.
Like, I've got this big belly,
I've got this big face still.
And then I started camping,
and I was dead near the several cameras.
I was like, "Oh, my God, I wouldn't say we talked about
"for anything."
And then, when I started doing a bit more,
and people loved me,
but it would give me compliments and stuff.
I was like, "Oh, I don't need to snap back."
Like, I love my body even more now,
'cause it's literally just give me a beautiful little baby boy.
I don't need to be back on my old clothes.
Like, I like me now.
And even though I have now lots of waste,
it didn't matter if I did or if I didn't.
I was happy with myself then,
and I'm still happy with myself now.
So, yeah, it's basically a study of Jackson's
in the background as well.
I tried in the corner, so I can't see me.
Thank you, that is so lovely.
That's so nice.
And that's so true,
because even when people are being nice,
you know, and I'm still guilty of it,
even though I'm consciously trying not to do it.
But even when people are being really nice,
they're like, "Oh, look, if you lost weight,
you look amazing."
Like, if we're constantly reinforcing, aren't we?
That like, you have to be skinny to be like,
skinny is good and healthy.
And like, "Oh, wow, you lost weight."
Like, even when people are saying nice things,
it's not really nice,
'cause it's reinforcing that you should be a certain way,
isn't it?
Yeah.
I felt like I had to be a sirens too,
like walking out the hospital with the car,
see, so it was just like, "Oh my God,
why do I still walk pregnant?"
So that was proper.
I was up, I was trying to start the gym,
like six weeks, I have to get to bed,
'cause I was bad, I'm unhappy.
Instead of just spending time at home with the baby,
I was like, "Now we need to get me in clothes."
'Cause I asked him just before something,
and I was like, "Oh, no, like, I need to be bikini desi."
And a month, like, but then after that,
I ended up loving, like, me big boobs,
when I had the milk in them,
I ended up loving me curvy body.
And I actually have missed it now.
I'm like, I'll be safe themselves then,
then I'll do it now.
I'm like, and in the very beginning, I did.
And so I didn't appreciate it at all,
'cause I was just like, "Now, wasn't like it."
Mm.
Yeah.
We never know what we've got at the time, Dewey, as well,
like, you can look back on pictures of yourself
and be like, "Oh my God, I remember feeling like,
I've looked fat there, but I was amazing."
Yeah.
That's literally how I look at, like, pictures of me
and the baby, like, when he was a newborn,
like, I felt awful.
And I think I look amazing.
On and on now, I can really, I can.
It's the thing that made me, like, stop forcing myself
in the gym and just chillin' up.
I was at home and stuff, because, like,
especially all the users, as well,
'cause I remember the first time,
like, I put, like, a picture in the chat
and if I was like, "Oh my God, you look amazing."
And I was like, "Oh."
And it is just such a confidence boost.
Yeah.
Oh, I'm so glad that, like,
the girls could be there for you, as well,
to help you to feel confident.
You are beautiful, as well.
It was everyone, honestly.
I've never known, like, a few for like girls in the community.
That all looks so different.
Yes, all are so, like, solid 10/10s.
(both laughing)
Yeah, we're so beautiful.
Like, everyone's beautiful.
Oh, thank you, Charo.
That's so nice.
And it's so nice to, like, see a few of you
that were at the photoshoot that we can,
'cause, like, I feel like this call is an extension of that,
'cause we just, we're just loving on each other,
fancy in each other, like,
just lifting each other off and it was so nice.
Um, Georgia.
Not a lot to, like, put you on the spot or anything,
but do you, do you want to say anything about you,
about your, like, journey with your body?
Yeah, okay.
I spoke a little bit before,
so I thought maybe I'll let the other speaker own him.
Talk too much on this spot, yeah, sure.
Okay, so I would say,
my story on body image,
I think just, like, making better choices
just makes me feel better about my body, like,
so, for example, I could be, like,
doing really well in the gym and eating good,
and then, like, I'm feeling good,
because, obviously, you know,
all of the good endorphins that get released
when you're training and eating good food,
but then I could have, like, a week of not eating good
and not training, and say,
and then I just feel completely different,
although my body looks the same,
like, probably looks the same in that week,
because you're not gonna change that much in just one week.
I just feel, like, just so different and so shit about it,
and then I will literally train, like, once,
and I'm like, oh, yeah, my bum's come back,
and my abs are coming back,
and even though it hasn't from one training session,
I feel like it's just, like, a mental thing, you know what I mean?
So, I think my body confidence comes from a healthy lifestyle,
and, to be honest, my, looking at my body in the mirror,
I'm now, I'm, like, so happy with it,
but I'm still not, like,
it's not exactly where I want it to be,
but I'm still really happy while I'm on the journey,
you know what I mean?
I still like to grow my bum a little bit bigger.
I know I talk about this all the time,
but it's coming, I feel like my GCL is coming.
I want it a little bit bigger,
but it's, like, it's okay that it's not at the moment,
because I still look at myself and think,
I'm happy with my body, I'm proud of my body,
and I know that I'm doing good by my body, you know what I mean?
So, I think that's, like, where my body confidence comes from,
it's just living a healthier lifestyle,
because I think to myself as well,
like, I never used to think this way when I was younger,
but these bodies, like, we're in these for the rest of our lives,
if we like it or not,
and we want to feel free and able and pain-free
and obviously confident and all of those things about it,
you know, and if I'm making bad choices
and not eating correctly or, you know,
not training and not stretching,
not, like, meditating and doing all these things
that I know is good for the body
and good for your mind, too, of course,
but also your body.
And then, yeah, then I'm like,
what am I really doing, you know,
just letting my body just, like, feed next stuff,
that's not good for it.
So, yeah, I think my body confidence just comes down to,
and just looking after myself,
because, yeah, we've only got one body, haven't we?
So, it's less about really what it looks like now
and more about what I'm putting into it.
But, obviously, that's the good effect that comes with it,
like, with being healthy and eating good food,
then the byproduct of that is that you're
probably gonna be happy with your appearance, too,
because your body's gonna thank you for that
with how it looks, you know?
So, yes, that's my little story,
but I didn't always feel this way.
I used to not feel so good about my body,
especially, like, when I love back on pictures
from when I was, like, in lockdown,
when I was living in Spain.
Oh, my God, I love back on pictures,
and I'm like, what did I do to myself?
But it was just, like, I just see on healthiness,
when I look at those pictures now,
I just see an unhealthy body, like, unhealthy minds.
But, yeah, that's my little story.
- Thank you, thank you.
And I think, like, I was talking,
we talked about it so much over the years,
haven't we, like, our bodies?
And we both, we both, like, become, over the past few years,
like, super conscious and super healthy.
And so, that's been a factor for both of us,
hasn't it, in, like, accepting ourselves.
But I think, apart of it for me as well,
it's been, like, you know, sometimes you be like,
"Oh, like, I want to, I want to grow my legs."
Like, "I want, I love your legs."
And I'd be like, "Oh, my God, my legs are big."
Like, "I want your legs."
Like, we're, like, just, like, each of us
sometimes want what the other ones got.
And then thinking, "No, actually."
Like, "Yeah, I am okay with myself."
I have, you know, I don't need to always look
for what I haven't got.
I can just look before what I have got sometimes.
So it helps us to have friends around you
that are saying those things, isn't it, things?
- Definitely, yeah, that's right.
We do look at the things that we don't have to be,
like, I just said, then I don't have a big bomb.
But, you know what, I actually do,
and I've got a healthy body,
and I've got, like, you know, all of these things,
so I need to, yeah, look at the things that I've got for sure.
It's good to be reminded of that.
- Yeah, maybe we should go around and say,
"We should all say something we like about our body."
Maybe that'll be a nice thing.
You wanna start, Jay?
Tell us something you like about your body.
- Okay.
What I really like about my body right now,
and what it's been, like, for a while,
I am noticing, like, more definition than ever,
and I feel stronger than ever.
Like, I'm getting back.
I'm getting my strength back after spending some time,
not in the gym for a while,
when I first got to Australia.
It's a bit all over the place.
Now, I feel like I'm getting stronger,
and I'm seeing, like, definition, like, in my abs,
and, like, in my legs, and I'm like, "Yes!"
So, yeah, that's what I love about my body.
One of the things.
- Thank you.
Oh, gosh, like, what do I love about my body?
I love that I have a strong body,
because I think there's been times
where I've not loved the fact that I have, like, big thighs,
and stuff like that.
But now, I have a strong, muscly body,
and I feel grateful for that.
And I also love my boobs.
(laughs)
- We all love your boobs.
- Lifeline!
- It's pretty thin.
- Laura, what do you love about your body?
- I like me bum.
I always have.
I've always had a nice, good handful of ass, really, so.
I like that.
And I think more than me bum, I like me smile.
I always get a lot of, I get more compliments
about me smile on camp than anything else,
even more than the spitties.
So, smile.
'Cause I smile a lot. (laughs)
- Thank you. (laughs)
- Hey. - Yes.
- Hello.
- Can you tell us something you like about yourself,
about your body?
- Well, I know if I didn't have this body,
I know it's old now, but I couldn't have done
all the things I've done in my life
unless it was strong and healthy.
And I'm still going at this ripe old age, so.
- Yeah, yeah. (laughs)
Thank you, Jen.
Are you grateful to your body
for all of those experiences?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Who else have we got?
Chloe, do you want to do you want to tell us
something you like about your body?
- Yeah, me belly, 'cause that was at one point,
the place that I hated the most.
And I feel like now that I'm in a good place,
I'd like to say, me, barely, and I could do.
I'm housed, me, baby, so now.
And other than that, me bum,
'cause it makes me the most lonely on camera.
(laughs)
- Thank you.
Anybody else?
I don't think anyone else has got their cam on,
but does anybody else want to say something
they like about their body?
- I love my boobs.
- Thanks, Christine.
(laughs)
- Hey.
- Okay, well, we'll move on now, shall we?
And have a look at a couple of the other slides.
So, really nice to hear from some people though.
So nice to hear from people of, you know,
what they're thinking about their body,
the lovely things.
Okay, so,
so a few self-love practices or even just self-acceptance,
we've talked about some of this stuff before,
haven't we, so, but, you know,
you can never talk about this stuff enough, really.
Affirmations, I mean, that's just what we've done just there,
isn't it, just, you know,
recognizing what we like about our bodies.
Self-awareness of being aware of the way we're speaking
to ourselves, you know, and just being conscious about it.
Sometimes I catch myself, like judging myself,
and then I correct it, I'm like, oh yeah, you know,
I don't actually think that, you know.
Self-compassion, having healthy role models,
like, the way your Instagram feed looks is so important,
isn't it, for your own body image?
I know it is for me.
I follow, like, loads of body positive people,
and anyone that just makes me feel like,
shit, I just unfollow them,
because it's just constant messaging, isn't it,
that's coming in.
Treating yourself, and self-touch, both of those things.
You like to use, like, nice lotions and stuff, don't you,
Georgia, like, you know, to nice yourself
and have a bit of a pamper there.
- Yeah, definitely, I think it's nice, isn't it,
to massage ourselves, and like,
when you put on cream on, like, do it with intention,
you know what I mean, and like, do it with like,
really just put good energy into your body,
while you're, like, massaging it on, you know.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I love that.
- And like, you know, like, really just take it to time,
you know, really just feel all over yourself.
- It's literally, like, a sex part,
even when no one's looking, right?
- Well, yeah, exactly.
I liked where, like, nice underwear,
I wear nice underwear every day, even though I'm on my own.
So most of the days, no one's seeing it, pamper cam.
But I just think it makes you feel so nice.
It's like the first nice thing to do for yourself
in the morning.
And yeah, accepting compliments,
that's something that I've tried to, like,
make a habit of as well.
Like, 'cause we're so, like, if we get a compliment,
so, like, oh, no, like, or, you know,
oh, this, this whole thing or whatever.
But I think, like, accepting compliments
and actually letting yourself, you know,
internally accept them, like, oh, yeah, thank you.
Yeah.
You know, it's such a nice thing to gift your body
with, isn't it?
So actually accept those compliments.
It's like a gift to yourself.
You should be able to accept them, you know?
And I thought we could just, just to, just to touch on,
you know, confidence on cam.
Obviously, we're here in this, like, little square, you know?
Can I ask a question?
I've got a ring light, but I don't know
where the best place to put it.
Yes.
I don't know what, where, whether I should have it
in the corner at an angle to me or what, I don't know.
Yeah. So I would say, behind your laptop.
And that's the best place.
Is that what you'd say, Georgia?
Just right behind your laptop.
Yeah, I would say so.
I've just put mine, click mine on now just to show the difference.
I've just put mine behind my laptop and clean it on.
Don't know if you can see me.
Yeah. Can you see me?
Yeah.
No, it's better, like.
Yeah, it's so much better, isn't it?
Like, it just makes a huge difference.
So just behind the laptop, my one's got two on, this one.
So you can, like, position it in different ways, you know,
and leave him just behind, pointing at ya.
And I would say that's a nice position for sure.
You make a huge difference, it's so worth it.
And you get them really cheap back home as well.
Pardon you, you get them on Amazon and stuff like that.
Super cheap.
So it's definitely worth, like, the small investment
that you're making.
Yeah.
It's just, I don't already have one of those,
but you keep up on it.
Yeah, I normally like to, so I have my ring light
behind my laptop.
And I'll also edit, like, the light on the actual laptop.
I'll edit that up and down to get the most flattering.
Like, I didn't know you could do that.
Yeah, there should be just a little bit, right?
Yeah, like a little, this little bottom of the little sun,
it looks like a little sun on it, it should be.
So you can do that up and down.
All right.
But yeah, normally have the ring light behind,
and then behind me, obviously, don't come here normally,
but I'll have, like, a lamp or, like, George
has got the lovely pink light behind her.
'Cause I think sometimes having a little low light
behind you and a big light in front of you is a good,
it's quite nice, isn't it?
It likes you up quite well.
I'll have a go tomorrow.
Yeah, 'cause I think just the main light
can wash it out a little bit.
Whereas if you have one in the background as well,
it kind of, like, balances it out.
Do you know what I mean?
So you look more free, David,
then just washed out, like, a blank image.
Yeah, yeah, that's what our science works best.
Yeah, but just play with it, isn't it?
And see what you feel most comfortable in, you know?
Yeah.
Yeah, I feel free to, like,
put message in the group or ask questions
or whatever, you know, everyone.
Yeah.
(indistinct)
I'll tell you what I find hard on camera,
is there's a little picture of me,
I can't see them,
and then they want me to type everything.
Because I have to have me glasses on, I can't see.
Is there any way around that?
You can, if you go out, go and see.
Yeah, I was just gonna probably say
the same thing you were gonna say.
You can make this the font even big, like, really big.
I think you can have it, like, actually quite huge, so.
Yeah, I have got it huge, but when you're typing, it's small.
Oh, yeah, but when you're typing, it's small, isn't it?
Oh, when you're actually typing.
But maybe you don't have to see it.
Like, if you know, can you see your laptop when you're typing,
or do you mean even your laptop keys are small?
Like, the keys are too small to see.
Me eyes, I'm gonna get me eyes checked,
'cause I think, 'cause I'm at a computer all day long,
I think they're getting worse.
Yeah, you know.
And I find it hard to tie.
You can Zoom your own screen in
to make your own writing bigger as well,
not just that is.
Oh, oh, yeah, if you Zoom the whole scene.
Yeah, I'll figure that out and I'll try,
I'll let Kay know how to do it.
I'll message you.
I'll message you probably tomorrow afternoon, Kay,
to go through it.
Oh, thank you, darling.
All right, my love, thank you.
Thank you.
Okay, that's really kind.
Yeah, okay, okay.
So, yeah, that's lighting.
Good angles, obviously, you know,
it's good to know the angles
that are most flattering for you when you're on camera.
Of course, you know, we've all got angles that we don't,
we don't feel look so good.
So, I always say I get like a crick,
crick, I crick my neck,
'cause I'm like, 'cause I know that my neck,
like a certain angle, like, I just look sexier.
And then sometimes everything calls,
I'm like, go like this,
'cause I've like been shot like that for ages.
I think it helps with your confidence
to know what your angles are, doesn't it?
Obviously, experimenting with makeup styles
and contouring is good.
Like, if I'm going on cam,
if you see me in reality,
I look like a clown,
'cause my makeup's just not,
it's not good for like reality,
but on cam, I know it looks good.
Like I've got loads of concealer on or,
right, red lipstick or whatever.
Like, if someone walks in,
I might look a bit dodgy,
but I make up a bit different for cam,
'cause I just feel it looks, it looks better.
I know like, it's one of the girls
was saying that she even contours,
like she contours her body and stuff,
which I thought, "Oh, that might be quite nice
"and I seem to do really," to like,
"I'd run out of contour."
You know, obviously we don't want to be going silly
and putting loads of extra things in your room,
'cause you know, you can jump on cam, you know,
however, in your pyjamas
and you'd still, you know, you'd still be fine,
but there's things, little things like that,
like can bring you confidence then it's okay, isn't it?
And dressing for your own comfort and your own pleasure,
you know, that gives you more confidence as well.
Have you seen my bedroom?
Look, all my uniforms.
Can you see?
Can you see how I think?
Yeah, kind of.
I saw a few uniforms at the weekends.
I know.
She was ahead of me.
I look totally different, don't I?
I've got myself ready for bed, that's why.
Okay, I'll look totally different tomorrow.
And then, I think,
oh, I thought it was the last slide, but there's one more.
So, yeah, just to, I suppose, reiterate
what we've said before.
What are your clients looking for, you know?
There's not one type of webcam model, as we always say.
There's lots of different types.
And, you know, different clients have different tastes
like different things.
Clients are looking for a fantasy.
So, they're looking for a fantasy,
but they're also looking for a connection
with a real person.
You know, they could be watching porn,
but no, they've come to talk to you to connect with you.
So, they want to see a real person.
You know, they don't want to see, you know,
a porn star, necessarily.
They want to see a real person
who they can connect with and chat to.
They want to fulfill their unique tastes.
So, you know, whatever their thing is, you know,
they've come here with that in mind, haven't they?
So, not assuming that we know what is attractive to clients,
'cause we don't.
You know, different things are attractive
to different people.
Obviously, they want to be able to have fun
and relax with you, which can only happen
if you're feeling fun and relaxed as well.
And they want to break from the expectations
of the outside world.
So, that's about energy, isn't it?
It's about, you know, connection and energy
rather than appearance, you know?
And then, Sammy, this was your,
Sammy sent this picture over,
and these words over today,
'cause she says she likes them
and I thought they were really, really nice.
So, I thought, you know, we'll end the call on a lovely note
and read out this little thing that's only found.
Thank you, Sammy.
So, from today, I refuse to agree to conform
to life confined to the prison of sociable norms.
I no longer agree to be shrouded in shame
from my past experiences or the size of my brain.
We all have flaws, both seen and unseen,
from the people we've met and the places we've been.
So, here's to a future where we're able to be
whoever we are and totally free.
Lovely.
Thank you, Sammy. That was nice, wasn't it?
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you so much for everyone sharing.
It was so nice to hear from everyone
about, you know, our unique experiences
and to be able to support each other.
And please do, you know, use the community,
post in the group or whatever
if you're feeling self-conscious
or if you want a pep talk or advice or anything at all.
So, thank you all, lovely ladies.
Nice to see you in here from you all again.
Yeah, thank you for coming, Kay.
It was lovely to see you.
That was a big one, everyone. I was completely at the box to the others.
You were a lovely day, with the lovely, lovely girls.
Very nice.
Hi, ladies. Have a nice evening. We'll see you all soon.
Good night. Bye, bye. Bye, everyone.
Bye. Bye. Yeah.